BRANDON M. HAMMOND

610 Broad Elk San Antonio, TX 78253 770-845-3627 Bhammond437@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Four years of experience in the Signals Intelligence community within the Department of Defense. Great work ethic, integrity, and energetic self-starter. Accustomed to working within a team or alone with no difficulty in completing tasks in a timely manner. Leader and Military Veteran with a Top Secret/SCI clearance who is mission-focused and detail-oriented. Constantly working to improve skills in order to be the most valuable asset in mission.

CORE SKILLS

- Strategic Planning / Analysis
- Oral / Written Communication
- Risk Management
- Critical Problem Solving
- Leadership
- Self-Development
- Communications / Signals Intelligence
- Intelligence Analyst
- Trainer / Mentor
- Data Analyst
- Technical Expert

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Navy Information Operations Command (NIOC)/National Security Agency, San Antonio, Texas

Multi-Disciplined Language Analyst Target Analyst July 2020 – Present

- Followed and analyzed assigned targets to determine the value of intelligence received.
- Translated foreign language materials into English and assisted in the issuing of SIGINT reports to high-level consumers.
- Trained new personnel in Targeting and Analysis.
- Introduced tools and methods used in previous missions to enhance analytic capability.

Navy Information Operations Command (NIOC)/National Security Agency, San Antonio, Texas

Fleet Information Operation Command Direct Support Operator Battle Watch Operator Cryptologic Analysis and Support Element Operator December 2017 – July 2020

- Cryptologic Direct Support Element Linguist / Analyst
- Assisted Cryptologic Analysis and Support Element Leading Petty Officer in keeping the Cryptologic Resource Coordinator and Command 4th Fleet informed of Red Force capabilities and equipment.
- Assisted in the stand up of 24/7 Distributed SIGINT Operations providing Indications & Warnings and Force Protection.
- Deployed with US Coast Guard to conduct training and counter drug operations in SOUTHCOM AOR.
- Deployed with US Navy to assist in providing Indications & Warnings and Force Protection.
- Qualified as a Battle Watch Operator to monitor ship activity within the SOUTHCOM AOR.

Information Warfare Training Command Monterey, Monterey, California Language Training School February 2017 – December 2017

Hammond Kitchen & Bath

Countertop Fabricator/Installer November 2010 – December 2016

- Measured countertops in existing homes to create plans for fabrication of new countertops.
- Worked with clients on scheduling tear-out/install dates.
- Led a team of three workers in fabrication of commercial and residential countertops.
- Responsible for forklift operation during deliveries.
- Drove work vehicles to various locations across the United States for delivery and installation.

Nistworks

IT Expert for Carroll County Government Facilities Installer/Operator October 2009 – November 2010

UNCLASSIFIED

- Responsible for maintaining security of sensitive information housed on local government computers and servers.
- Maintained/Installed/Updated software on local government systems.
- Repaired damaged government computers and installed new ones as necessary.

Oak Mountain Golf Course

Cook

February 2009 - October 2009

- Prepared food for daily operations.
- Cooked and prepared all orders that came through the kitchen.
- Assisted in maintaining inventory of all food items.
- Managed two cooks in daily operations.

T.J. Maxx

Seasonal Sales Associate Seasonal Stocker December 2008 – February 2009

- Unloaded deliveries weekly and sorted all items.
- Stocked all delivery items in their proper locations.
- Assisted customers in finding specific items.
- Responsible for operating a register as needed.

Zaxby's

Cook

December 2006 - December 2008

- Prepared food items prior to daily restaurant opening.
- Learned and worked all stations in the kitchen in order to help if needed.
- Responsible for cleaning and sanitation of entire kitchen.
- Responsible for four kitchen employees and quality control.

Southwire

Temporary Employee for Release of New Product Packager

June 2006 - December 2006

- Participated in testing of flat wire concept.
- Worked with a crew of five individuals, packaging product samples sent out to company representatives.

Sears

Warehouse Worker Sales Representative Delivery Assistant March 2004 – May 2006

- Assembled floor model products daily.
- Organized warehouse on receipt of shipments.
- Prepared appliances for delivery daily.
- Modified delivery routes to increase driver's productivity.
- Learned about all appliances in order to help customers with any questions.
- Assisted in sales during busy operational hours.

EDUCATION

- AA in Spanish, Defense Language Institute 2017
- 12 credits towards Bachelor's Degree in Science, Focus in Web Design & Development, Full Sail University 2020-present
- Various National Cryptologic School Courses related to SIGINT (Reporting, Traffic Analysis, Cryptanalysis, Target Development) as well as Information Technology and Telecommunications

AWARDS

- Army Achievement Medal x 2, 2017
- Global War on Terrorism Service Medal, 2019
- Good Conduct Medal, 2019
- Navy/Marine Corps Achievement Medal, 2021

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request

Case number (RES-2021-11128)